- [Instructor] In this part, we discover the selectors
that we use to calculate derived data based on the state,
based on existing state.
So let's look at the syntax for the selectors.
That's going to be quite similar to the atom.
This will accept a unique ID as the key,
and we're going to get this get property
to return computed state.
So we're going to make some logic here,
which is to first access, read from existing states
from state contained in one atom.
And we're going to return
and combine this state with this information.
So we can read the font size information with the unit,
the corresponding unit, which is px.
So let's go back to our project.
We're going to create also some derived data
by using the selectors,
so I'm just going to remove the useStates.
What we've done so far is to replace
the use of the useState with useRecoilStates,
and we're going to use also now selectors
to create derived data.
So right here I'm going to create the new selector
which will be listItems, and that's going to be selector.
We're going to have one key,
so I'm going to name it also listItems.
And we're going to get a property, which is get.
And we're going to have access to this method gets,
and with this get method,
we're going to read from existing state.
First we want to return the lists, the full list of items,
so that's going to be get,
and remember that we have an items
that contains the state for all the items,
so that's going to be all states.
And we also need the information
about whether or not the list is filtered.
So that's going to be a boolean,
and that's going to be based
on the existing state of this boolean.
So that's going to be a if.
We're going to add an if statement inside the selector.
So we're going to do also some logic
to return computed states based on existing states.
So what we're going to do is, if this is true,
we're going to filter the list and only return the item
that are marked as done, like this.
Otherwise, we return the full list of items.
And next, what we want to do is to read from this listItems.
So what we've been using is useMemo.
That also allows to returns computed states, computed data.
So what we want is to no longer use the react API,
so I'm going to remove this one.
I'm just going to keep the allItems name,
and I'm going to use another hook from recoil,
which is useRecoilValue, this one,
and I'm going to pass this listItems selector
to allow to read from this computed state.
So let's just make sure that this is added here,
useRecoilValue, let's go back,
and now we have access to the all items.
Perfect, so let's try that.
So I already have my app, which is up and running
and looks like I still have my list, okay.
So I can also filter and only filter out items
that are not completed
to display underneath the items marked as done, perfect.
So there is another variable that we want to define,
which is, isVisible, and this is based
on whether there is items that are marked as done
that we're going to allow to display this button.
So instead of using useMemo,
we're going to use also a selector that's going to be isVisible,
and this one is going to be also a selector.
This one is going to be isVisible.
We also going to have access to a gets.
And for this one, we want to actually,
I'm going to say isVisible but first what we would like
is to I'm going to change the name to itemsCounts,
because basically it's going to be based
on whether there is accounts which is existing,
so I'm going to change this.
So first, we're going to do list.
We're going to read from the states.
It's going to be listStates, and we're going to iterate
through the list and return if there is any items
that are marked as done with the some.
And if it's true, we're going to then read
from this computed state, and we're going to read
with useRecoilValue and pass itemsCount, that should work.
Let's try that, going to test, so here it goes.
So this is working perfectly, so we can display the items
which are marked as done only and display this button
only if we have items that are marked as done.
This one, excellent.
So there is this also this one that we're not using,
so instead of using useRecoilState, we just need to update.
We just need to update the states,
so we could use this hook and replace with filtering.
That's another hook from the recoil API.
That allows here, so let's just make sure
that this is added to the scope.
This is useRecoil,
useRecoilSet, useSetRecoilStates, like this.
So let's just make sure that we use this one,
because we just need to update the state in this instance.
A selector represents a piece of derived data.
Derived data is a powerful concept,
because it allows to build dynamic data
depending on other data, existing data.